A Finding Aid to the James Brooks and Charlotte Park Papers, 1909-2010, bulk 1930-2010, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1926-2001; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, OV 20
  - Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key (Box 4)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, James Brooks (1972 May 10-June 25), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Dan Flavin Art Institute, The Drawings of James Brooks, 1946-1978 (1984 June 28-November 30), 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Elaine Benson Gallery, Inc., Some Major Artists of the Hamptons Then and Now: 1960s-1980s (1984 June 16-July 3), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Finch College, James Brooks (1975 April 29-June 8; 3 other venues 1975 June-November), 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Galleria Lorenzelli (1975 June 4-30, 1977, and 1978), 1975-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gruenebaum Gallery (1981 April 7-May 2), Guest Book, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Gruenebaum Gallery (1983 October 18-November 12), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Gruenebaum Gallery (1986 June), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Gruenebaum Gallery (1988 April), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - The Heckscher Museum, Curator's Choice (1986 August 23-September 28), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Heckscher Museum, James Brooks: A Quarter Century of Work (1988 July 9-August 28), 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, Five Distinguished Alumni – The WPA Federal Art Project: An Exhibition Honoring the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Centennial (1982 January 20-February 22; another venue 1982 March 13-April 18), 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery (1972 November 7-December 16), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Parrish Art Museum, Curator's Choice (1985 September 28-November 10), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - The Parrish Art Museum, Drawing on the East End, 1940-1988 (1988 September 18-November 13), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - The Parrish Art Museum, Painting as Landscap e (1985 August 3-September 22), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Phoenix II, First Anniversary Exhibition (1982 December 7-1983 January 15), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Portland Museum of Art (Maine), James Brooks: Paintings and Works on Paper, 1946-1982 (1983 May 8-September 20), 1981-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26-28)
    - Robinson Gallery, James Brooks (1976 January), 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Vereo Gallery (1988 September 3-22), Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Fellowships, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Fellowships, National Endowment for the Arts, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Formulae and Mixes, circa 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Gruenebaum Gallery, circa 1979-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
  - Guston, Philip, 1966-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Lettering, 1953; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Lettering by Brooks, 1926-1930s; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in OV 20 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Murals, circa 1935-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - National Academy of Design, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - National Arts Club Medal (1985), 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Pollock, Jackson, 1951-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Projects, Mural, Archival Resource Key (Box 4)
    - Hempstead, N.Y. Post Office, circa 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - LaGuardia Airport, Flight, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
      - Explanation of Flight including Medium Used in Painting the Mural, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Landmarks Preservation Commission Report, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Notes, circa 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Publicity, circa 1940-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4-10)
      - Record Book, circa 1940-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
        Includes time, date, materials and media, dimensions, models, and inventory of materials.
    - Little Falls, N.J. Post Office, 1938-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Little Falls, N.J .Post Office and Woodside, L.I., Library, Account Book, 1934-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Records costs, materials, and methods.
    - Woodside, L.I., Library, 1936-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Projects, Painting Commission – Mobil Oil Corporation Headquarters, Fairfax, VA, circa 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - References from Brooks for Other Artists, circa 1973-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, circa 1966-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Teaching, Miscellaneous Locations, circa 1947-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Teaching, Pratt Institute, circa 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Teaching, Queens College, circa 1967-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Teaching, University of Pennsylvania, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Transatlantic Trip on Saturnia, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Lettering by Brooks from Box 4, Folder 38, 1930-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 20)
- Personal Business Records, 1932-1992; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 5-6
  This series records transactions concerning Brooks' artwork – conservation, gifts, loans, sales, and shipping. Gallery records include agreements, consignments, lists, receipts, etc. Also found are personal tax returns and an account book regarding early lettering work and income.
  Similar documentation may be found in some subject files (Series 6). Business records dated after Brooks' death that concern his artwork are found with the Charlotte Parks papers (Series 11).
  - Accounts for Lettering, 1932-circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Appraisals, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Art Supplies (Sources, Services), circa 1977-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Bills, Paid, 1958-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Conservation, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Contract Form, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Gallery Records, Archival Resource Key (Box 5)
    - Alex Rosenberg Gallery, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Berenson Gallery, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Berry-Hill, 1986-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Carone Gallery, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Lerner-Heller, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Gifts, 1980-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Insurance, 1949-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Loans to Exhibitions, 1962-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mailing Lists, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Names for Paintings and Lists of Used Names, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photo Lists, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Prices, circa 1970-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Prints, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Sales, 1966-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8-11)
  - Sales, Samuel M. Kootz Gallery Inc., 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Shipping Receipts, circa 1960-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Shipping Receipts, Samuel M. Kootz Gallery Inc., circa 1959-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Studio Expenses, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Tax Returns, 1946-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Warehouse, 1966-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Printed Material, 1928-1992; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4.8 Linear feet Boxes 6-11, OV 21-OV 22
  Most printed material mentions Brooks or includes reproductions of his work; a small amount concerns other artists – friends, former students, and a few others. Articles include reviews and feature stories that appeared in newspapers and periodicals. Miscellaneous printed items consist of book jackets and calendars featuring reproductions of Brooks' paintings, conference programs, announcements of shows for which Brooks served as a juror, an exhibition prospectus and entry form, political and anti-war tracts, and advertisements for Brooks exhibitions.
  Printed material, arranged by record type, is alphabetized by folder title.
  - Announcements of Lectures, Symposia, Miscellaneous Events, 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Articles, 1928-1992; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in OV 21. (Box 6, Folder 19-30)
  - Articles, 1981-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1961-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Collection Catalogs, 1961-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1951-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10-16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, circa 1936-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17-23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, 1954-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1-19)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, 1963-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, 1977-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-13)
  - Invitations, 1965-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Maps, 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, circa 1958-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Museum Publications, 1952-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals, 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Periodicals, It Is (nos. 1-6), 1958-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19-21)
  - Press Releases, 1957-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Print Catalogs and Print Portfolio Announcements, 1970-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Print Workshops, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reproductions, Artwork by Brooks, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Reproductions, Artwork by Others, undated; Archival Resource Key; Oversized material housed in OV 22. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Statements on Modern Art, 1950; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Articles from Box 6, Folders 19-21, circa 1943-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 21)
  - Oversized Reproductions of Artwork by Others from Box 11, Folder 4, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 22)
- Artwork, 1930s-1992; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 11
  Artwork by Brooks is comprised primarily of drawings in pencil and ink, loose and in two undated sketchbooks. Volume 1 is comprised of pencil sketches, mostly of figures and heads; Volume 2 consists of abstract compositions drawn in ink. Also found are "telephone doodles." Work by others consists of an ink drawing with watercolor wash by Paul Fligel inscribed to Brooks, an ink drawing of his sculpture by Adolph Gottlieb, three pencil drawings of Brooks by Philip Guston, two silhouettes of Brooks by William King, and a gouache painting on paper by an unidentified artist.
  - By Brooks, Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
    - Drawings in Pencil and Ink, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Drawings in Pencil and Ink; Bookplate (print), 1930s-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Sketch in Tempera, Mural Project, The Acquisition of Long Island, Woodside Library, 1930s, Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Sketchbooks, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Telephone Doodles, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - By Other Artists, 1948; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Photographic Materials, 1909-2000s; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 4.1 Linear feet Boxes 11-15
  Photographic materials consist of photographs, digital prints, negatives, slides, and color transparencies. Subjects are artwork by Brooks, exhibition installations, people, places, and miscellaneous subjects.
  Photographs of people include Brooks, Park, and others. Among the identified individuals are: Barry Adabody, L. Adams, Giogrio Cavallon, Julie and Peter Cochran, Sivon Conaty, Cile Downs, Betty and Julian Eisenstein, Ruth Judge, Judy Braude Kahn, Ibram and Ernestine Lassaw, Conrad and Anita Marcarelli, Sanford and Arloie McCoy, Tino and Ruth Nivola, John and Estelle Opper, Barbara Park, Syd Solomon, and the Watsons. In addition, there is a copy of Nina Leen's 1950 portrait of "The Irascibles" that appeared in Life. Also of note is a picture of unidentified attendees at a dinner at LaGuardia Airport on the occasion of the dedication of Flight.
  Among the places appearing are Brooks' homes and studios in Montauk, New York, and East Hampton, New York. Views of the Middle East, taken during World War II, include Brooks and army colleagues, scenery, and views of local people engaged in daily activities. Travel pictures are of Maine, Italy, California and Oregon; those taken in Oregon include some of Park's relatives. Miscellaneous subjects are cars, pets, lettering and type.
  This series is arranged by subject; within each subject, filing is alphabetical by folder title. Most of the material has been removed from binders and placed into archival folders. All original order has been maintained.
  - Artwork by Brooks, Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
    All files may include photographic prints, digital prints, slides, negatives, and/or transparencies.
    - Artwork by Brooks (executed 1930s-1960s), circa 1933-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Artwork by Brooks (executed 1970-1974; slides), 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Artwork by Brooks (executed 1975-1987) and Exhibition Installation (1981), 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Paintings and Drawings of the Middle East produced for the Army Artists' Program of the U.S. Army Historical Division (executed 1942-1945), 1997; 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper, La Guardia Mural (executed 1930s-1942), 1930s-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper, La Guardia Mural (executed 1930s-1942), 1930s-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1946-1949), 1940s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1950-1954), 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21-23)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1955-1959), 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1960-1961), 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1962-1963), 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1964-1966), 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1967-1969), 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1970-1974), 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1974-1979), 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Paintings/Works on Paper (executed 1980-1986), 1980s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Works on Paper (executed 1947-1980s), 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Works on Paper (executed 1951-1986), 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
    - WPA Mural, The Acquisition of Long Island, Woodside Library, circa 1938-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - WPA Mural, Flight, LaGuardia Airport (executed 1938-1942), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - WPA Mural, Flight, LaGuardia Airport (executed 1938-1942), circa 1979-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - WPA Mural, Flight, LaGuardia Airport, Restoration and Rededication Ceremony 18), 1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Photographic album (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - WPA Mural, Hempstead, N.Y. Post Office (designed 1934; not executed), circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - WPA Mural, Labor and Leisure, Little Falls, N.J. Post Office (executed 1938), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Installations; Family Portrait, 1982; Work by Other Artists, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14-17)
    - Artwork by Brooks (executed 1950s-1970s) for Slide Lecture, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition Installations, Kootz Gallery; Martha Jackson Gallery, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Exhibition Installations, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibition Installations, 1972-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Exhibition Installations, 1985-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Exhibition Installations, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - People, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
    - Brooks, 1909-1910; 1940s-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Brooks with Colleagues in Egypt; Views of People, Daily Life and Landscapes, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9-10)
    - Brooks with Others, 1940s-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Brooks and Park, 1950-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Brooks and Park with Others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Others, Identified, 1937-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Others, Unidentified, 1940s-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Places, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
    - Brooks' Homes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Brooks' East Hampton Studio, 1994; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Huckstep and Atlantic Crossing (U.S. Army), 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Italy, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Maine, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - The Middle East, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - Bengazi, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Egypt, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Palestine, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Unidentified Locations, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24-26)
      - Unidentified Locations, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - Montauk House and Studio, 1954; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Montauk House Move to Springs (slides), 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Oregon and California Trip; Oregon, 1968; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Springs House and Studio, circa 1968-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified, circa 1967-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1969; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, Lettering and Type, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1949; undated; Archival Resource Key; 9 Rolls of negatives (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Katie and Everett at Headeck House, Charles at Fire Island (1 roll); Montauk '49, Interiors – Zackery, Beach Scenes (1 roll); Park Family (children) at Greene, New York (1 roll); Yorktown Heights, Eric and June Mose (1 roll); Untitled (5 rolls).
  - Unidentified Negatives, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Charlotte Park papers, 1930s-2010; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 15-18, OV 23
  This series is comprised of the professional and personal papers of Charlotte Park, Abstract Expressionist painter, art teacher, wife of James Brooks and executor of his estate.
  Biographical materials include notes about Park and other family members, copies of her birth certificate, and resumés.
  Correspondence consists of personal and business letters addressed to Charlotte and to the couple. In addition, there is correspondence concerning James Brooks' estate, posthumous exhibitions, and other business matters. Also found are copies of the correspondence of curator Meg Perlman and of Julie Lawrence Cochran, Director of the James Brooks and Charlotte Park Brooks Foundation.
  Writings by Park include 3 notebooks. Also included are a diary kept during a trip to Japan, and miscellaneous notes. Writings by others are a catalog essay on James Brooks, a poem by Stanley Kunitz, and one by Hilda Morley written for Park's 1979 show at The Laundry.
  Among the subject files is documentation of Park's participation in the Art Lending Service of the Museum of Modern Art, her teaching activities, and interest in the women's movement. Other files concern The James Brooks and Charlotte Park Brooks Foundation, The Pollock-Krasner Foundation, Inc., and a James Brooks catalogue raisonné project. Exhibition files document Park exhibitions, posthumous Brooks exhibitions, and a show that included work by both.
  Personal business records include inventories, price lists, conservation records, sales, inventories, and gifts of artwork documenting Park's career, Brooks estate business and management of his artwork.
  Printed material consists of articles, exhibition announcements, catalogs, and miscellaneous items relating to Charlotte Park and James Brooks. Material concerning Brooks was published after his death.
  Artwork consists of two ink drawings: one by Abbott Pattison inscribed "St. Charlotte to me Abbott Pattison," and an unsigned portrait of an unidentified man.
  Photographic materials are photographs, negatives, slides, and color transparencies. Subjects are artwork by Park and views of a few Park exhibition installations. There are pictures of Charlotte Park alone and with friends, students, and her parents. Also found are views of the graves of various Hawkes-Park family members. A small photograph album consists of snapshots of Charlotte Park and Jim Brooks, unidentified friends, and cats.
  - Biographical Materials, circa 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, circa 1930s-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15-23)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Writings by Park, Diary of Trip to Japan, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Writings by Park, Notebooks, 1959-1963; 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Writings by Park, Notes, 1992; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Writings by Others, Catalog Essay, "James Brooks: The Strong, Silent Type" by Sara K. Rich, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Writings by Others, Poems, undated; 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)